* [Shop](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/shop/landing-page/) Menu Toggle
* [Train](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/) Menu Toggle
    * [Dancer training](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/dancer-training/) Menu Toggle
    * [Dance teacher training](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/dancer-training/dance-teacher-training/) Menu Toggle
* [Auditions](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/apply/) Menu Toggle
* [Participate](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/participate/) Menu Toggle
* [Information](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/information/) Menu Toggle

Main Menu

Privacy
=======

This privacy notice is in place to inform our audiences and supporters how we, The Royal Ballet School, may collect, use and protect their personal data. This is a supplemental notice to The Royal Ballet School’s privacy policy and has been created to provide guidance specifically to our audiences and supporters. Staff; current, past and prospective students; and their parents, carers or guardians, are advised to read the full privacy policy.

##### [Read the full privacy policy](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Privacy-Policy-20-May-2019.pdf)

### Who we are

The Royal Ballet School acts as the data controller for the purpose of Data Protection Law.

Registered Address:

46 Floral Street  
Covent Garden  
London WC2E 9DA

Registered Charity Number: 214364

### When do we collect personal data?

The term ‘personal data’ is any information relating to an identified or identifiable living individual.

We collect and use personal data in order to give our audiences and supporters the best possible experience of The Royal Ballet School. We are committed to being honest and respectful in collecting and using your personal data.

We may collect personal data when you:

* book onto one of our events, courses or performances
* make a donation
* sign up to our e-newsletter
* join as a Friend of The Royal Ballet School
* respond to a survey or online form
* visit us and/or speak to a member of staff or a volunteer

### What personal data do we collect?

The type of information we collect depends on the reason for your relationship with us.

We may collect and hold:

* your full name
* your contact information including email address, telephone number and postal address
* your contact preferences
* financial information
* transaction and order details
* demographic information
* still and moving images taken during your visit
* other information relating to surveys or feedback
* alumni information including photographic images taken during your training here at The Royal Ballet School

We do not collect special category personal data from our audiences and supporters relating to their health, race, religious beliefs and political opinions unless there is a clear reason for doing so, such as providing additional access requirements at an event, course or performance. We only use this information to ensure we provide the best possible level of service and enable you to continue engaging with us.

Depending on your settings or privacy policies for social media like Facebook, LinkedIn, Instagram or Twitter, you may give us permission to access information from those accounts or services.

### How we may use your personal data

We always endeavour to be fair and transparent with how we use your information and ensure at all times that your information is protected.

The personal data you provide may be used:

* to provide a service or fulfil a purchase (including Friends subscriptions, events and course bookings)
* to process payments by debit/credit card or by setting up direct debits
* for fundraising purposes (see Fundraising section below)
* for alumni purposes (see full privacy policy)
* to invite you to participate in relevant surveys
* for marketing purposes when specific consent has been given
* to better understand your preferences in order to tailor our communications to suit your interests
* to analyse and improve the services we may provide
* for security purposes, including CCTV in accordance with the School’s CCTV policy
* to act in accordance with the School’s [safeguarding and child protection policy](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Safeguarding-Policy-30-January-2018.pdf)

We will not hold more information than required and will ensure all personal data held is kept up to date and used only for its specific purpose(s) outlined above. The retention policy will vary according to the purpose and may be contingent on circumstances when required to keep the data on the grounds of legal obligation and legitimate interest. Please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for further information on how long we may keep your data.

We will not sell, rent, trade or distribute your personal data to any third parties for marketing purposes unless we have received your prior permission to do so.  Data may be shared with trusted service providers who are authorised to act on the School’s behalf and have entered into data processing agreements with us. These services may include payment processing, event ticketing, database services, website hosting and email delivery services. In these circumstances your data will only be used for the agreed purpose relating to the service that they are providing. We do not transfer any personal data to countries outside of the European Economic Area (EEA).

### Legitimate interest

We may occasionally hold or use personal data on the grounds of ‘legitimate interest’. In broadest terms, this means that we can process personal information if we have a genuine and legitimate reason and we are not harming any of your rights and interests.

Before using this basis, we carefully consider and balance any potential impact on you and your rights.

Please see the full Privacy Policy for further information.

### How we protect your personal data

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any personal information retained is kept confidential and stored in a secure, password protected, database that is only accessible by relevant members of staff.

We will take appropriate technical and organisational steps to ensure the security of personal data about individuals, including policies around use of technology and devices, and access to School systems. All staff and governors are aware of the privacy policy and their duties under Data Protection Law and continue to receive relevant training.

### Fundraising

As a registered charity, we rely on funds raised from a variety of different sources including individuals, companies, charitable trusts and other grant-giving bodies. The generosity of these supporters enables the School to train exceptionally talented young dancers, from around the world, regardless of their economic background.

Where we believe there is ‘legitimate interest’, we may seek additional information before contacting individuals or companies to determine whether there is a suitable reason to engage with them, such as a shared interest or potential connection. We may also use public research to better understand the interests of our current supporters and Friends so we may improve our communication and suggest relevant opportunities to increase engagement with us. Additionally, we may hold and process professional details of individuals who are corporate subscribers when there is a legitimate interest to do so. This could be to seek further information from a company or grant giving body regarding a funding opportunity or to follow up with an organisation to keep them informed of programmes which they have funded.

We endeavour to tailor communication and improve the experience our supporters and Friends have with the School. To do this we may segment personal data provided (for example in order to send an invitation to contacts geographically located close to the event location), analyse donations made to The Royal Ballet School and access publicly available information to build a profile of interests and preferences (this might include: LinkedIn, Companies House, Charity Commission, amongst other legitimate media sources).

You can request that your data is not used for this kind of profiling and/or unsubscribe from future communications by contacting [\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### Your rights

Wherever you are asked to submit personal data there will be an option for you to select the type of communications you wish to receive and in some cases how you wish to be contacted. You have the right to update your preferences at any time by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

The accuracy of your personal data is important to us and you have the right to update the personal data that we hold. Please help us keep our records up to date by notifying us when your personal data changes by contacting [\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

If you ask for your data to be removed, we will keep the minimum amount of information to ensure we adhere to your request. Please note however that we may have a lawful reason to hold or use the personal data in question which does not require consent.

You have the right to ask us not to hold or use your personal data however this does mean we may not be able to provide you with the full range of services that are offered.

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, or after 25 May 2018, the General Data Protection Regulation, you have the right to request full details of your personal data that is held by us. To make this request please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), including a description of the information you would like to see together with proof of identity.

### This notice

We will update this notice from time to time. Any substantial changes that affect your rights will be provided to you directly as far as is reasonably practicable.

### Questions

If you have any comments or question concerning this notice please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

If you have reason to believe that we have not complied with this notice of the full privacy policy or acted otherwise than in accordance with Data Protection Law, they should utilise the School complaints procedure and should also notify [\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). The School can also make a referral to or lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), although the ICO recommends that steps are taken to resolve the matter with the School before involving the regulator.

Search for: 

* [Shop](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/shop/landing-page/) Menu Toggle
* [Train](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/) Menu Toggle
    * [Dancer training](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/dancer-training/) Menu Toggle
    * [Dance teacher training](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/dancer-training/dance-teacher-training/) Menu Toggle
* [Auditions](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/apply/) Menu Toggle
* [Participate](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/participate/) Menu Toggle
* [Information](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/information/) Menu Toggle

* [Shop](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/shop/landing-page/) Menu Toggle
* [Train](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/) Menu Toggle
    * [Dancer training](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/dancer-training/) Menu Toggle
    * [Dance teacher training](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/dancer-training/dance-teacher-training/) Menu Toggle
* [Auditions](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/train/apply/) Menu Toggle
* [Participate](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/participate/) Menu Toggle
* [Information](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/information/) Menu Toggle

Shopping Basket

Contact the Royal Ballet School
-------------------------------

+44 (0)20 7836 8899

[\[email protected\]](https://www.royalballetschool.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

46 Floral Street, Covent Garden, London, WC2E 9DA, UK

Quick Links
-----------

© 2024 The Royal Ballet School | Registered charity no: 214364

### Start typing and press enter to search

Search
